Let me begin my story in a world where
假设有一个场景
a robot resides and let's assume the robot has no clue where it is.
其中有个机器人 它不知道自己在哪
Then we will model this with a function,
我们用函数模拟此场景
I'm going to draw onto this diagram over here.
在这里画个图表
Where the vertical axis is the probability for any location in
垂直轴表示这个场景中
this world and the horizontal axis
任何位置的概率
corresponds to all the places in this one-dimensional world.
水平轴表示这个一维场景中的所有位置
The way I am going to model the robot's current belief about where it might be,
对于机器人目前认为自己所在的位置
it's confusion is by a uniform function that
我用一个单值函数的模型来表示
assigns equal weights to every possible place in this world.
该函数为此场景中的每个潜在地点都分配相等的权重
There is the state of maximum confusion.
即最大迷惑状态
Now to localize the bot has they have some distinctive features,
要进行定位 这个场景必须具有一些独特的特征
let's assume there's three different landmarks in the world.
假设有三个不同的地标
There's a door over here,
这里有道门
there's a door over here and a third one way back here.
这里有道门 这里是第三道门
And for the sake of the argument let's assume they are all look alike.
为了方便讲解 假设它们看起来都一样
They're not distinguishable, but you can
没有区别
distinguish the door from the none door area from the wall.
但是可以与非门区域区分开 例如墙壁
Now let's see how the robot can localize itself by assuming it senses,
我们看看机器人如何定位自己
and it senses that it's standing right next to a door.
假设它能够感知 能感知自己站在门边
All it knows now that is located likely next to a door.
它现在只知道自己可能位于门边
How will this affect our belief?
这会如何影响到我们的信念？
Here is the critical step for localization.
下面就要讲到很关键的定位步骤了
If you understand this step you understand localization.
如果你理解这一步 就理解定位了
The measurement of a door transforms our belief function,
门的测量值将由潜在位置定义的信念函数
defined over possible locations to a new function.
转变成了一个新的函数
It looks very much like this.
看起来差不多是这样的
For the three locations adjacent to doors,
对于靠近门的三个位置
we now have an increased belief of being
我们更加相信自己靠近这里
there whereas all the other locations have a decreased belief.
而所有其他位置的信念降低了
This is a probability distribution that assigns
这是一个概率分布
high probability for being next to a door and it's called the
为靠近门的位置分配更高的概率
posterior belief with the word posterior means it's after a measurement has been taking.
称为后验信念 也就是在测量之后的信念
Now the key aspects of this belief is that we still don't know where we are,
这个信念的关键之处是我们依然不知道自己在哪
there's three possible locations and in fact,
有三个可能的位置
it might be that the sensors were
实际上 传感器可能出错了
erroneous and we accidentally saw a door where there is none,
我们不小心看到门 但实际上没有门
there's still a residual probability of being at these places over here,
但是依然有位于这些位置的残留概率
but these three bumps to get them really express our current best belief of where we are.
这三个峰值共同表示了我们对所在位置的当前最佳信念
This representation is absolutely core to probability and to movable localization.
这个表示法是概率和移动定位的绝对核心概念
Now let's assume the robot moves.
现在假设机器人移动了
Say it moves to the right by a certain distance,
移动到右侧一定距离
then we can shift the belief according to the motion.
我们可以根据该动作调整信念
Anyway this might look like is about like this.
看起来可能是这样的
This pump over here, made it to here.
这个峰值移到了这里
This guy went over here and this guy over here.
这个移到这里 这个移到这里
Obviously this robot it knows it's heading direction,
很明显 机器人知道它的移动方向
it's moving to the right in this example.
在这个示例中是往右侧移动
But it knows roughly how far it moved.
大概知道移动了多远
Now robot motion is somewhat uncertain,
机器人动作不确定
we can never be certain where the robot moved.
我们永远无法确定机器人移到哪了
These things we will be a little bit flatter than these guys over here.
这些峰值变得稍微平坦些
The process of moving those beliefs to right are essentially called a convolution,
将这些信念往右移动的流程称为卷积
and let's now assume the robot senses again and for the sake of
现在假设机器人又开始感知了
the argument let's assume it sees itself right next to a door again,
为了方便演示 假设它再次看到自己位于门边
so the measurement is the same as before.
测量结果和之前一样
Now the most amazing thing happens.
现在是最神奇的时刻了
We end up multiplying our belief which is now prior to the second measurement,
我们将信念（现在在第二个测量结果之前）
with a function looks very much like this one over here,
乘以一个函数 看起来像这样
which has a peak at each door and outcomes it believes it looks like the following.
它在每个门那有一个峰值 结果看起来像这样
There's a couple of minor bumps but the only really big bump is this one over here.
有几个小的峰值 最大的峰值是这个
This one corresponds to this guy over here in the prior and it's the only place in this
对应的是先前的这个峰值 是这个先前结果中
prior that really corresponds to the measurement of
真正对应有门测量结果的位置
a door whereas all the other places of doors have a low prior belief.
所有其他有门的位置信念都很低
As a result this function is really interesting,
因此 这个函数非常有趣
it's a distribution that focuses most of
它是一个分布 将大部分权重放在此处
its weight under the correct hypothesis of the bot being on
前提是机器人位于第二道门边的假设正确
the second door and it provides very little belief to places far away from doors.
并且对远离门的位置信念很低
At this point our robot has localized itself.
此刻机器人定位到自己在哪了
If you understood this,
如果你理解了这一点
you understand probability and you understand localization.
就理解了概率和定位
Congratulations, you understand probability and localization.
恭喜 你明白概率和定位了
You might not know yet,
你可能还不知道
but that's really a core aspect of
但是这是理解我今天将在课堂上讲解的
understanding a whole bunch of things I'm going to teach you in the class today.
很多知识的核心概念